Finding Aid for Frank Murphy Oral History Project, 1963-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank Murphy Oral History Project 1963-1968
Michigan Historical Collections.
1 linear foot (in 2 boxes)
87174 Bimu C445 2
Transcripts of oral interviews conducted by University of Michigan history professor Sidney Fine in cooperation with the Michigan Historical Collections with individuals on the subject of the life and times of Michigan governor and U.S. Supreme Court Justice, Frank Murphy; and sound recordings of the interviews.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
These interviews were conducted by Professor Sidney Fine and different staff members of the Michigan Historical Collections. Donor no. 6419.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Frank Murphy Oral History Project was undertaken by the Michigan Historical Collections (now the Bentley Historical Library) and University of Michigan history professor Sidney Fine who was researching for a multi-volume biography of Michigan Governor and United States Supreme Court Justice Frank Murphy. The purpose of the interviews was both to supplement the Frank Murphy papers and to provide further information about Murphy's life and career.
The transcripts of the interviews are arranged alphabetically by interviewee. The collection also includes the tapes of some of the interviews.
Subjects:
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Fine, Sidney, 1920-
Contributors:
Fine, Sidney, 1920-; Brennan, John V., 1872-1971.; Chawke, Thomas F.; Davidow, Lawrence S.; Devitt, Joseph.; Gellein, Hilmer.; Goldstick, Nathan.; Hayden, Elizabeth Olivia Hall.; Hayden, Martin Scholl, 1912-; Hedetniemi, Charles J.; Hill, Norman Hingston, 1887-1971.; Lawton, James Frederick, 1888-1969.; Manning, John C. (John Charles), 1893-1967.; Mead, Harry H.; Mortimer, Wyndham, 1884-1966.; Muller,Carl, 1900-; Muller, William.; Norton, William J. (William John), 1883-1975.; Pack, William Clarkson, 1896-1970.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968; Pressman, Lee, 1906-1969; Radow, Carl.; Reuther, Roy L., d. 1968.; Travis, Robert, 1905-1978.; Wilson, Nel.; Yost, Eunice Josephine Fite, 1881-1975.
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.; Sound recordings.
- Interview transcripts
  - Thurman Arnold. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Marvin Petroelje December 15, 1964 (Box 1)
  - James V. Bennett. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner December 15, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Justice Hugo Black. Report by Robert M. Warner on an interview with Justice Black October 21, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Justice Hugo Black and William O. Douglas. Report by Robert M. Warner on interviews with Justices Black and Douglas October 21-22, 1964 (Box 1)
  - John V. Brennan. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner December 9, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Thomas F. Chawke. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine March 1965 (Box 1)
  - J.H. Creighton. Interview conducted by Marvin Petroelje and Richard Ortquist 1964 (Box 1)
  - Larry Davidow. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine May 12, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Joseph Devitt. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine July 14, 1966 (Box 1)
  - William O. Douglas. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner October 22, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Report by Robert M. Warner on an interview with Justice William O. Douglas October 22, 1964 (Box 1)
  - James A. Farley. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner November 11, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Hilmar Gellein. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Richard M. Doolen August 21, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Nathan Goldstick. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner December 9, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Eugene Gressman. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner October 21, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Joseph R. Hayden. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine February 15, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Charles J. Hedetniemi. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner October 20, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Norman H. Hill. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Richard Doolen August 21, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Holtzoff. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner October 20, 1964 (Box 1)
  - G. Donald Kennedy. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Marvin Petroelje May 11, 1965 (Box 1)
  - J. Fred Lawton. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine November 26, 1965 (Box 1)
  - MacDonald. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine (Box 1)
    (topics include Flint politics, Sitdown strike, the Flint Alliance)
  - Matthew McGuire. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner October 19, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Jack Manning. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Marvin Petroelje December 4, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Harry Mead. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Richard Doolen August 15, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Harry Mead. Interview conducted by Richard T. Ortquist June 8, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous memoranda of interviews by Sidney Fine (Mrs. Jaffe, Justice Black, and Judge Schweinhaut) (Box 1)
  - Wyndham Mortimer. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner December 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Irene Murphy and Sharon Murphy Keyes. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner July 30, 1964 (Box 1)
  - William J. Norton. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner July 27, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Philip C. Pack. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner September 7, 1965 (Box 1)
  - John J. Pickering. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine October 19, 1964 (Box 1)
  - James Kerr Pollock. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner July 12, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Frank Potts. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine January 8, 1965 (Box 1)
    (topics include Frank Murphy in Harbor Beach; personal life of Murphy)
  - Lee Pressman. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner November 12, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Roy Reuther. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine July 12, 1966 (Box 1)
  - John Rogge. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner November 13, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Social workers (Josephine Gomon, Mary Lutomsky, Irene Murphy, and Beulah Carter). Interview conducted by Sidney Fine (Box 1)
  - Robert Travis. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner December 10, 1964 (Box 1)
  - G. Mennen Williams. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine December 1964 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Nel Wilson. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine July 5, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Fielding Yost. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Robert M. Warner October 28, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Martin Hayden, Carl Muller, Carl Radow, and William Muller of the Detroit News. Interview conducted by Sidney Fine and Marvin Petroelje, October 6, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Stenorette recordings of some of the interviews (Box 2)
  - Sound recording of joint interview conducted by Sidney Fine with Josephine Gomon, Irene Murphy, and others, May 17, 1972, 1 sound tape; 3 3/4 ips; ca. 2 hours (Box 2)
    There is also a cassette copy of this interview; there is no transcription.